

Oleksiy Letushev

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

PROFILE

A web developer specializing in front end with a bachelor's degree in computer science. Bringing 2 years of experience, deep understanding of HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, as well as strong skills in writing clean and efficient code for high-quality solutions.

EDUCATION

2016 - 2020

Taras Shevchenko National University of Kyiv Bachelor of Computer Science Faculty of Computer Science and Cybernetics Department of Theory and Technology of Programming

SKILLS

- · HTML | semantics, accessibility
- CSS | SCSS, BEM, responsive design
- JavaScript | ES6+, Ajax, REST, Canvas API
- React | Redux / MobX, routing, hooks
- · Git & GitHub
- Webpack
- Basic experience: GraphQL, jQuery, Bootstrap, PHP, Node.js, PWA, Photoshop
- · Intermidiate level of English

COURSES

2018 [5 months]

Front-end course | Kottans

Learned Git & GitHub, Linux and command line, network basics, and created 4 projects using Webpack, HTML, CSS, and vanilla JavaScript.

CONTACTS

• **Telephone**: +380937119697

• Email: o.m.letushev@gmail.com

• Portfolio website: letushev.github.io/portfolio

• GitHub: https://github.com/Letushev

EXPERIENCE

Aug. 2018 - May 2019

Front-end developer | ЛУН

- Worked on a big multilingual project Flatfy (Korter), which provides information about real estate in 11 countries.
- Transformed a multi-page project (jQuery) into a single-page application with React, MobX, and styled-components.
- Implemented responsive and cross-browser HTML/CSS layouts, new user-facing features, performed bug fixes, and improved codebase quality.
- Developed a lot of new reusable React components, managed front-end data state and proper communication with a server.
- Worked in an agile team of designers (Sketch), back-end developers (PHP and Node.js), and content specialists to meet project goals and create effective user experiences.

Aug. 2019 - Jun. 2020

Math teacher | ЯвКурсі

Prepared more than 40 students for a math exam.

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

In my spare time, I love playing the guitar, watching movies, listening to music, or doing any kind of sport, especially running. Also, I am keen on hiking.